Inventory of the Carter Family Papers 1667-1862
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- People Files, 1667-1862. (Folder 1-102)
  - Carter, (Robert W.) 1792-1861; 1803-1862, n.d. (Folder 20-101)
    - Letters, 1803-1861. (Folder 20-50)
      - Letters, 1851-1852., 64 items. (Folder 38)
        - J. M. Smith, at Heathsville, [Northumberland County], to [Col. Robert W. Carter], 16 June 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - William T. Jesse, at Nuttsville, [Lancaster County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, 2 July 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - Gordon Forbes, at Sandy Point, to Col. R. W. Carter, 7 July 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - A. B. Allen & Co., at New York, to [Robert W. Carter ?], 26 July 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - R. H. Lyell, at Farnham Church, [Richmond County], to Col. [Robert W.] Carter, 7 Aug 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - J. M. Harris to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 13 Aug 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - Robert W. Carter to J. M. Mason, 5 Sept 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - E. Conway, at Fredericksburg, to [Robert W. Carter], 10 Sept 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - Pierpont Seymour, at E[ast] Bloomfield, N. Y., to [Robert W.] Carter, 24 Sept 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - E. Conway, at Fredericksburg, to [Robert W. Carter], 14 Nov 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - John H. Elmore, at Union Village, Northumberland County, Virginia, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 14 Nov 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - William D. Nelson, at Afton, near the Hague, Westmoreland County, to Col. Robert W. Carter, near Warsaw, Virginia, 14 Nov 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - C. Midhard[?], at Philadelphia, to [Robert W. Carter], Nov 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - James P. Pare, King George [County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 8 Dec 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - S. Corning Judd, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Virginia, 12 Dec 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - James P. Pare to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 23 Dec 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - Brockenbrough & Boughton, at Tappahannock, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 26 Dec 1851., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - Vestrymen of the Parish of Lunenburg, [Richmond County], to the Right Rev. William Meade, [Bishop of the Diocese of Virginia]. [1851]., 1 item. Draft. (Folder 38)
          Draft of a statement concerning the resignation of Rev. William N. Ward as Rector of Lunenburg Parish. Note: The draft is in the handwriting of Robert W. Carter.
        - G. W. Lewis, at Claymont, [Westmoreland County], to Col. R. W. Carter, 14 Jan 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - Landon C. Berkeley, at Bushfield, Westmoreland [County], to Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw Post Office, Richmond County, Virginia, 16 Jan 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - R. S. Hipkins, at Tappahannock, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 30 Jan 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - Landon C. Berkeley, at Farnham Church, Richmond County, to [Col. R. W. Carter], 7 April 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - J. M. Mason, at Washington, to Col. [Robert W.] Carter, 13 May 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - John S. Braxton, at Warsaw, to Col. R. W. Carter, 9 July 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - Austin Brockenbrough, at Tappahannock, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 9 July 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - James Cooke & Co., at Fredericksburg, to Col. Robert W. Carter, 12 July 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - Thomas S. Lyell, at Union Village, [Northumberland County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, 24 July 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - Wat H. Tyler, at Wilton, to Col. [Robert W. Carter], 24 July 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - G. H. Miskell, to Col. [Robert W.] Carter, 25 July 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - E. Conway, at Fredericksburg, to [Robert W. Carter], 7 Aug 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - Thomas Jones, Jr., to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 9 Aug 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - P. Seymour, at East Bloomfield, N. Y., to Robert W. Carter, 13 Aug 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - P. Seymour, at East Bloomfield, Ontario County, [N. Y.], to Robert W. Carter, 28 Sept 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - W. H. Coffin, at Durrettsville, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 7 Oct 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - P. Seymour, at East Bloomfield, N. Y., to [Robert W. Carter], Oct 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - C. H. Hunt, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, 20 Nov 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - F. Slaughter, at Fredericksburg, to Col. Robert W. Carter, 30 Nov 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - Austin Brockenbrough, at Tappahannock, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 10 Dec 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - H. W. Daingerfield, at Tappahannock, to Col. R. W. Carter, 10 Dec 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - P. Seymour, at East Bloomfield, N. Y., to Robert W. Carter, 20 Dec 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - Edward T. Tayloe, at Powhatan Hill, [King George County], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Xmas of 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
        - F. W. Pendleton to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 28 Dec 1852., 1 item. (Folder 38)
      - Letters, Jan - June 1853., 38 items. (Folder 39)
        - 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - Thomas S. Waugh, at Warsaw, Virginia, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 6 Jan 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - John R. Taylor, at Fall Hill, near Fredericksburg, to Col. [Robert W. Carter], 13 Jan 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - W. Woodville & Sons, at Baltimore, to Col. Robert [W. Carter], at Warsaw, 19 Jan 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - Armistead N. Wellford, at Fredericksburg, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 28 Jan 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - Edward T. Tayloe, at Powhatan Hill, [King George County], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 7 Feb 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - John T. Lackey, at Heathsville, Virginia, to Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 17 Feb 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - John R. Taylor, President, Old Dominion Steam Boat Co., at Fredericksburg, to [Col. R. W. Carter ?], 17 Feb 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - J. R. Lowry to Col. Robert W. Carter, 18 Feb 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, to C. H. Hunt, Secretary, Old Dominion Steam Boat Co., [at Fredericksburg], 21 Feb 1853., 1 item. Copy. (Folder 39)
        - C. H. Hunt, Secretary, Old Dominion Steam Boat Co., at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, 25 Feb 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - Edward T. Tayloe, at Powhatan Hill, [King George County], to Col. [R. W. Carter], 8 March 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - C. H. Hunt, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, 10 March 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - A. Brockenbrough, at Tappahannock, to [Col. R. W. Carter], 11 March 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - E. Conway, at Fredericksburg, to R. W. Carter, 11 March 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - William H. Richardson, at Richmond, to Col. R. W. Carter, 11 March 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - M. L. Eliason, at Upperville, [Fauquier County], to her brother, [Col. R. W. Carter], 19 March 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - William N. Ward, at Bladensfield, [Richmond County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, 24 March 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - R. W. C[arter] to William N. Ward, 30 March 1853., 1 item. Copy. (Folder 39)
        - Dones Clarke, at Boston, Mass., to Col. R. W. Carter, 31 March 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - James P. Dun[?] to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine [Hall], 1 April 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - Wat H. Tyler to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 11 April 1853., 1 item. Mutilated. (Folder 39)
        - H.H. Lewis, at Washington, to R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Virginia, 12 April 1853., 1 item. Mutilated. (Folder 39)
        - J. Brown, Jr., at Richmond, to Col. Robert W. Carter, Richmond County, 14 April 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - W. F. Murren, at Warsaw, to [Robert W. Carter], 29 April 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - M. L. Eliason, at Crednal, to her brother, [Col. Robert W. Carter], 30 April 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - Edmund Withers, at Lancaster Court House, Virginia, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 30 April 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - R. L. T. Beale, at Cabinford, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 4 May 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - Landon C. Berkeley, at Bushfield, Westmoreland County, Virginia, to [Col. R. W. Carter ?], 6 May 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - David C. Moore, at Lexington, Virginia, to Col. Robert Carter, 11 May 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - John Gooding to Col. Robert W. Carter, Richmond County, 19 May 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - C. H. Hunt, at Fredericksburg, to Robert W. Carter, 27 May 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - R. Sinclair & Co., at Baltimore, to R. W. Carter, 28 May 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - A. N. Wellford, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 6 June 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - A. N. Wellford, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 12 June 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - H.H. Lewis, at Washington, to R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Virginia, 16 June 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - John Hooff, at Alexandria, to [Col. R. W. Carter?], 20 June 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
        - John J. Rollow & Co., at Fredericksburg, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 24 June 1853., 1 item. (Folder 39)
      - Letters, July - Dec 1853., items. (Folder 40)
        - M. L. Eliason, at Crednal, to her brother, [Col. R. W. Carter], 9 July 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - Fowle & Co., at Alexandria, to Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw P. O., Virginia, 13 July 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - W. B. Webb to [Col. R. W. Carter ?], 16 July 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - G. W. Lewis, at Claymont, [Westmoreland County], to Col. R. W. Carter, 23 July 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - William H. Tayloe to Col. Carter, 27 July 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - G. W. Lewis to Col. R. W. Carter, 28 July 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - Landon C. Berkeley, at Bushfield, [Westmoreland County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Warsaw P. Office, Richmond County, 2 Aug 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - C. H. Hunt, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, 8 Aug 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - John J. Rollow, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, 9 Aug 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - G. W. Lewis, at Claymont, [Westmoreland County], to Col. R. W. Carter, 10 Aug 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - John T. Lackey, at Heathsville, [Northumberland County], Virginia, to Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 17 Aug 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - Samuel Sands, at Baltimore, to [Col. Robert W. Carter], 29 Aug 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - Egerton & Brother, at Baltimore, Maryland, to [Col. Robert W. Carter], 1 Sept 1853., 1 item. Printed circular letter. (Folder 40)
        - J. W. Hutt, at Montross, [Westmoreland County], to Robert W. Carter, 17 Sept 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - Benjamin Ogle Tayloe, at Washington, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Barnum's [Hotel], Baltimore, 20 Sept 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - G. W. Lewis, at Claymont, [Westmoreland County], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 24 Sept 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - J. A. Carter, at Upperville, to Robert [W. Carter], 29 Sept 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - F. D. Wheelwright, Westmoreland County, to Col. Robert W. Carter, 6 Oct 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - Abraham P. Wilson, at Oak Grove, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 10 Oct 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - E. C. Edwards, at Warsaw, to Col. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 12 Oct 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - J. A. Carter, at Crednal, to Robert [W. Carter], 15 Oct 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - Edward T. Tayloe, at Powhatan Hill, [King George County], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Warsaw, Virginia, 29 Oct 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - Charles W. Smith, at Tappahannock, to Col.[R. W. Carter], 4 Nov 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - R. C. Hammack to Col. R. W. Carter, 5 Nov 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - Edward T. Tayloe, at Powhatan Hill, [King George County], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 21 Nov 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - P. Thornton Lomax to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 22 Nov 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - P. Thornton Lomax, at Roseland, to Col. R. W. Carter, 23 Nov 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - William H. Tayloe to Col. [Robert W.] Carter, at Sabine Hall, 23 Nov 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - W. B. Webb to Col. Robert W. Carter, 24 Nov 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - R. S. Hipkins, at Tappahannock, Wo Robert W. Carter], 26 Nov 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - N. Wellford, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, 5 Dec 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - W. B. Webb to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 10 Dec 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - Seth F. Livingston, at Warsaw, to Col. R. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 13 Dec 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - J. R. Jeffries to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 19 Dec 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - Eustace Conway, at Fredericksburg, to [Robert W. Carter], 20 Dec 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - J. Brown, Jr., at Richmond, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Warsaw P. O., Richmond County, Virginia, 21 Dec 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - A. J. Brent, at Heathsville, [Northumberland County], to Col. R. W. Carter, 28 Dec 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - Francis B. Jones, at Carysbrooke, to Col. Robert W. Carter, 28 Dec 1853., 1 item. Mutilated. (Folder 40)
        - P. Thornton Lomax, at Opies, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 29 Dec 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
        - Eustace Conway, at Fredericksburg, to R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, 30 Dec 1853., 1 item. (Folder 40)
      - Letters, 1854. (Folder 41)
        - F. W. Pendleton to Col. Robert W. Carter, 18 Jan 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - B. W. Brockenbrough, at Tappahannock, Virginia, to [Col. R. W. Carter], 20 Jan 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - N. Wellford, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 6 Feb 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - H. W. Daingerfield, at Tappahannock, to Col. R. W. Carter, 10 Feb 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - William H. Tayloe to Col. R. W. Carter, 10 Feb 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - James W. Hipkins, at Tappahannock, to Col. [Robert W. Carter], 14 Feb 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - R. H. Lyell, at Farnham Church, [Richmond County], to Col. [Robert W. Carter], 14 Feb 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Edward C. Christian, at Warsaw, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 15 Feb 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - John W. Phillips to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 20 Feb 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - John R. Taylor, on board steamer Virginia, to [Col. R. W. Carter ?], 20 Feb 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - W. B. Webb to Col. [Robert W.] Carter, 1 March 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - J. E. Clemm, on board steamer Virginia, to Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 3 March 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - G. W. Goldsby, at Montross, [Westmoreland County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Warsaw, Virginia, 11 April 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - John J. Rollow, at Fredericksburg, to [Robert W. Carter], 11 April 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - G. W. Goldsby, at Montross, [Westmoreland County], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 12 April 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - John S. Trible to Col. [Robert W.] Carter, 14 April 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - John M. Whittemore, at Fredericksburg, to Robert W. Carter, 15 April 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - A. N. Wellford, at Fredericksburg, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 23 April 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - G. W. Lewis, at Claymont, [Westmoreland County], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 29 April 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - C.C. Lee, at Brookfield, to R. W. Carter, 8 May 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - G. W. Lewis, at Claymont, [Westmoreland County], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 10 May 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - M. L. Eliason, at Inglewood, to her brother, [Robert W. Carter], 18 May 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - John S. Trible, at Dunnsville, [Essex County], to Col. [Robert W.] Carter, 19 May 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Thomas B. Bigger, postmaster, at Richmond, Virginia, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Warsaw P. O., Virginia, 1 June 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - John Critcher, at Bankton, near Kinsale, [Westmoreland County], Virginia, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 24 June 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - G. D. Alderson, at Lancaster Court House, Virginia, to Col. Robert W. Carter, 28 June 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - William H. Tayloe, at Mt. Airy, [Richmond County], to Col. [Robert W.] Carter, 5 July 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - John Seddon, at Fredericksburg, Virginia, to Col. Robert W. Carter, 23 July 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - J. Brown, Jr., at Richmond, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Virginia, 6 Aug 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - William N. Ward, at Bladensfield, [Richmond County], to Col. R. W. Carter, 9 Aug 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - John T. Lackey, at Heathsville, [Northumberland County], Virginia, to [Robert W. Carter], 17 Aug 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - John T. Lackey, at Heathsville, [Northumberland County], Virginia, to [Robert W. Carter], 14 Sept 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - S. F. Livingston, at Kinsale, [Westmoreland County], Virginia, to Col. Robert Carter, at Warsaw, Virginia, 27 Sept 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Lawrason & Kelly, at Baltimore, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 28 Sept 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Robert W. Carter, to W. B. Webb, 4 Oct 1854., 1 item. Copy. (Folder 41)
        - Willoughby Newton, at Linden, [Westmoreland County], to [Robert W. Carter], 4 Oct 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - E. Conway, at Fredericksburg, to [Robert W. Carter], 9 Oct 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - R. S. Hipkins, at Tappahannock, to Col. R. W. Carter, 13 Oct 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Thomas P. Knox, at Fredericksburg, to Col. Robert W. Carter, 13 Oct 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Wat H. Tyler to Col. [Robert W. Carter], 14 Oct 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Two letters written on the same page, Oct - Nov 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
          Two letters written on the same page: Gordon Forbes, at Sandy Point, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 17 Oct 1854.
          Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, to Daingerfield Belfield, at Belle Brant, 10 Nov 1854.
        - G. W. Lewis, at Claymont, [Westmoreland County], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 17 Oct 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - P. R. Fendall, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 18 Oct 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Thomas F. Knox, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, 23 Oct 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Thomas F. Knox, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, 30 Oct 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, to P. R. Fendall, at Washington, 3 Nov 1854., 1 item. Copy. (Folder 41)
        - A. N. Wellford, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 15 Nov 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Virginia [Tayloe], at Washington, to [Robert W. Carter], 28 Nov 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - A. N. Wellford, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 1 Dec 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - William T. Jesse, at Nuttsville, [Lancaster County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, 7 Dec 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Elizabeth [Wellford], at Fredericksburg, to her father, [Robert W. Carter], 10 Dec 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - A. N. Wellford, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 17 Dec 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - R. W. C[arter] to G. W. Lewis, 18 Dec 1854., 1 item. Copy. (Folder 41)
        - Edward C. Marshall, at Alexandria, to Col. R. W. Carter, 19 Dec 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Philip A. Wellford, at Fredericksburg, to Col. R. W. Carter, 19 Dec 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - William D. Nelson, at Hague, [Westmoreland County], to [Robert W. Carter ?], 22 Dec 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - John M. Phillips, at Hermitage, [Prince Edward County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 22 Dec 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - H. P. F. King to Col. Robert Carter, 23 Dec 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - H. P. Mitchell, at Powhatan Court House, to Col. R. W. Carter, 23 Dec 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - S. Y. Connelley, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 25 Dec 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - Caty Newcombs Lo Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 25 Dec 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
        - John T. Lackey, at Heathsville, [Northumberland County], to Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 28 Dec 1854., 1 item. (Folder 41)
      - Letters, 1855., items. (Folder 42)
        - J. Brown, Jr., at Richmond, to Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, 1 Jan 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - J. Minor, agent, Franklin Fire Insurance Company of Philadelphia, at Fredericksburg, to Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, 7 Jan 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - Joseph H. Beacham, at Farmville, to Col. [Robert W.] Carter, 14 Jan 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - A. N. Wellford, at Fredericksburg, to Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 18 Jan 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - Gordon Forbes, at Sandy Point, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 7 Feb 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - Gordon Forbes, at Sandy Point, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 10 Feb 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - B[laden] T. Tayloe, at Powhatan, [King George County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, 22 Feb 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - B. T. Tayloe, at Powhatan, [King George County], to Col. [Robert W. Carter], 7 March 1855., 1 item. Mutilated. (Folder 42)
        - John M. Botts, at Richmond, to [Robert W. Carter], 8 March 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - John M. Harrison to Col. R. W. Carter, 16 March 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - E. C. Edwards, at Warsaw, [Richmond County], to Col. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 7 April 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - James B. Fones, at Louis Hill, to Col. R. W. Carter, 15 April 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - Edward T. Tayloe, at Powhatan Hill, [King George County], to Col. [Robert W.] Carter, at Sabine Hall, 16 April 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - J. & J. Williams, and J. W. Neuneberger, at Baltimore, to [Robert W. Carter], 19 April 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - J. A. Carter, at Crednal, to Robert [W. Carter], 23 April 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - G. W. Lewis, at Claymont, [Westmoreland County], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 25 April 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - Reuben T. Thom, at Fredericksburg, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Warsaw, Virginia, 28 April 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)
        - Wellford Eastham & Co., at Fredericksburg; to R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Warsaw P. O., Richmond County, 1 May 1855., 1 item. (Folder 42)